shopko.com 2008-09-15

# ShopKo : Legal Information

Copyright Notice  
Copyright © 2006 Shopko Stores Operating Co., LLC ("Shopko"), 700 Pilgrim Way, Green Bay, Wisconsin 54307. All rights reserved. The content, format, and imagery of this web site are copyrighted under United States law and protected by worldwide copyright laws and treaty provisions. Unauthorized duplication is a violation of law.

The contents of this web site may not be copied, published, broadcast, distributed or transmitted in any way without prior written consent of Shopko. Shopko reserves complete title and full intellectual property rights for materials downloaded from this web site.

 **Trademarks, Service Marks, and Trade Names**  
"Shopko" is a registered trademark of Shopko Stores Operating Co., LLC. Other names, logos, designs, titles, words, recordings or phrases on this web site may also constitute trademarks, service marks, trade names or other protected intellectual property of Shopko or other entities.

 **Limitation of Liability**  
The materials on this site are provided "as is" and with all faults. Shopko does not warrant that this web site or the server that makes it available are free from defects, bugs, viruses or other harmful components. To the fullest extent permitted by law, Shopko disclaims all express and implied warranties, including, without limitation, implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, and Shopko shall not be responsible for technical, hardware or software failures or damages of any kind, lost or unavailable network connections, incomplete, scrambled, illegible or delayed computer transmissions, or technical inaccuracies of the information provided on this web site. Shopko hereby expressly disclaims any liability for special, indirect, incidental, consequential or any other damages believed to have been caused by the use of this web site or any site linked to this site.  
The links provided on this site will allow you to leave Shopko's site and connect to sites which are not under the control of Shopko. Accordingly, Shopko can make no representation concerning the content of these sites, nor can the fact that Shopko has given you these links serve as an endorsement by Shopko of any of these sites. Shopko is providing these links only as a convenience to you; this is to inform you that Shopko has not tested any software found on these sites and therefore cannot make any representations regarding the quality, safety or suitability of any software found there. There are inherent dangers in the use of any software found on the Internet, and Shopko cautions you to make sure that you completely understand the risk before retrieving any software on the Internet. Thank you for your cooperation.

 **Forward-Looking Statements**  
Forward-looking statements made on this Web Page, if any, which may include statements about the future performance of Shopko and Shopko's plans, objectives and expectations or intentions are made under the safe harbor provisions of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These forward-looking statements are based upon management's assumptions and beliefs in light of information currently available to it and are subject to certain important factors which could cause results to differ materially from those anticipated by the forward-looking statements. These factors include those referenced under the caption "Forward-Looking Statements" in Shopko's current Annual Report on Form 10-K. Other risks or uncertainties may be detailed from time to time in Shopko's future Securities and Exchange Commission filings.

The following privacy statement applies to Shopko's website ("Shopko website" or "Site"), except for the portions of the Site which are operated by our retail partners and subject to their own privacy statements. In addition, when you use our Online Pharmacy, certain information you provide is subject to unique privacy standards as described in the Notice of Privacy Practices.

Shopko makes every effort to create an online environment that is safe, easy, and respects your privacy. We won't sell, rent or give information which identifies you personally ("personal information") to anyone if you've told us not to as described below. 

The rest of this statement outlines in more detail the kind of information we collect and what we do with it.  
1\. When you visit Shopko's website, our web server automatically recognizes your domain name, your computer's operating system, browser type, the address of the web page you're coming from and of those pages you visit on our Site. We use this data in the aggregate to determine how much our customers use parts of our Site so we can improve it. We may also match user information with offline data available from other sources in order to carry out our services and conduct our advertising and promotions more effectively. We do not automatically recognize or collect your name, home address or telephone number.   
2\. During your visit to Shopko's website, we use "cookies" to store and sometimes track information. A "cookie" is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Generally, we use cookies to remind us who you are and enable us to access your information so you do not have to re-enter it; gather statistical information about usage by registered or unregistered users; research visiting patterns; help target advertisements based on user interests; assist our retail partners in the tracking of visits and the processing of orders; and track the progress and participation in promotions. In some instances, our retail partners and advertisers appearing on our Site may use their own cookies. Preference and options configurations in your browser determine if and how a cookie will be accepted. You can change those configurations on your computer if you desire. By changing your preferences, you can accept all cookies, you can be notified when a cookie is set, or you can reject all cookies. If you do so and cookies are disabled, you may be required to re-enter your information more often and certain features on our Site may be unavailable.   
3\. Shopko's website uses contractors (other companies hired by us) to perform some services on our behalf. These contractors have access only to the personal information needed to perform these services, and they are prohibited from using such information for any other purpose.   
4\. When you register, enter a contest, participate in an e-mail program, fill out a survey, or make a purchase using a credit card, we or our contractors may collect some or all of the following information: your user ID, password, name, shipping and billing addresses, e-mail address, shipping and billing phone numbers, card type, card number, card expiration date, and optional personal information. This information is used by us or our contractors to bill you for your purchase, ship your order, send e-mail notices, or verify and ship a contest prize. It may also be shared with our vendors who co-sponsor a contest and our other retail partners only for the express purposes of our original intent.   
You can be assured that your credit card information and other data given during the order process will be guarded with the highest levels of security and confidentiality. All orders placed on our Site are encrypted using SSL technology, so your transactions are protected. With SSL in place for both the client and the server, the information sent via the Internet will be transmitted securely using the SSL technology. To be sure your connection is secure when filling out the order form, simply check for the padlock icon in the bottom border of your browser window. The icon should be visible and show the lock in the locked position.  
Important note: E-mail is not encrypted and is not a secure means of sending credit card information. Please place all orders through the order form or over the telephone. Do not attempt to e-mail an order.   
5\. We archive correspondence of those who communicate with us via e-mail. This information may be used to follow up with you. If you supply us with your postal address or telephone number online or via e-mail, we will use that address to contact you regarding information you requested.   
6\. We may use your personal information to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to statistically analyze site usage, to improve our content and product offerings and to customize our Site's content, layout, and features. We may also use your information to send you materials regarding our products, services and promotions. To "opt out", simply unsubscribe.   
7\. From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses. If our information practices significantly change at some time in the future, these changes will be reflected within the privacy policy you are reading now. It is our intent that at no time will your privacy be compromised, and you'll always be asked if you want to opt out of any of these new uses.   
If you have any comments or questions about your privacy while visiting Shopko's website, please feel free to contact us.   
Internet Privacy Policy last updated 12/8/06

 **Shopko and Shopko Express RX Notice of Privacy Practices**  
This Notice describes how medical information about you may be used and disclosed and how you can get access to this information. Please review it carefully.

We are required by law to:  
\- Make sure that protected health information is kept private.   
\- Provide you with this Notice of our legal duties and privacy practices relating to your protected health information.   
\- Follow the terms of the Notice that is currently in effect.   
\- Your protected health information may be used and disclosed for the purposes of treatment, payment, and healthcare operations and other limited circumstances.  
\- You have the following rights concerning your protected health information:  
\- You may request restrictions on certain uses and disclosures.   
\- You may obtain a copy of your health records.   
\- You may request alternate methods of communications.   
\- You may request amendments.   
\- You may request and receive an accounting of disclosures.   
\- You may obtain a copy of this Notice. 

**Privacy Practices**  
We are required by law to:  
Make sure that protected health information is kept private.  
Protected health information is information that identifies you and relates to your past, present, or future physical or mental health condition and related healthcare services.   
Provide you with this Notice of our legal duties and privacy practices relating to your protected health information.

The Notice also describes your rights with respect to protected health information about you.   
Follow the terms of the Notice that is currently in effect.

We reserve the right to change our practices and this Notice and to make the new Notice effective for   
all protected health information we maintain. Upon request, we will provide the revised Notice to you.

 **Uses and Disclosures of Protected Health Information**  
Your protected health information may be used and disclosed by our healthcare professionals who are involved in your care and treatment for the purpose of providing healthcare services to you. Your protected health information may also be used and disclosed to obtain payment for our services and to support the operation of our healthcare centers. 

The following are examples of ways we use and disclose protected health information:  
 **Treatment:** We will use and disclose your protected health information to provide you with treatment or services. For example, information obtained by us may be used to dispense prescription medications or eyewear to you. We also may use or disclose your protected health information, as necessary, to contact you to provide refill and/or appointment reminders or information about treatment alternatives or other health-related benefits and services that may be of interest to you. We will also maintain records related to the care and services provided to you. 

**Payment:** Your protected health information will be used, as needed, to obtain payment for your healthcare services. For example, we will contact your insurer or other third-party payer to determine whether it will pay for the services we provided to you and to determine the amount of your co-payment. 

**Healthcare Operations:** We may use or disclose your protected health information in order to support the operations of our healthcare centers and monitor the quality of the care we provide. For example, we may use information in your health record to evaluate the services our center provides or to provide training to our staff. We may also call you by name when your prescription is ready. 

Communication with individuals involved in your care or payment for your care: Using our best judgment, we may disclose your protected health information to a family member, other relative, or any person you identify relevant to that person's involvement in your care or payment related to your care. For example, if you send a friend or relative to pick up your prescription or eyewear, we may disclose your protected health information to him or her. 

**Other Uses and Disclosures**  
In some limited situations the law allows or requires us to use or disclose your health information for purposes beyond treatment, payment, and operations. Not all of these situations will apply to us; some may never occur at our healthcare centers. 

As required by law: We must disclose protected health information about you when required to do so by law. 

**Food and Drug Administration (FDA):** We may disclose to the FDA, or persons under the jurisdiction of the FDA, protected health information relative to adverse events with respect to drugs, foods, supplements, products and product defects, or post marketing surveillance information to enable product recalls, repairs, or replacement. 

**Worker's compensation:** We may disclose protected health information about you as authorized by law and as necessary to comply with laws relating to worker's compensation or similar programs established by law. 

**Public health:** As required by law, we may disclose your protected health information to public health or legal authorities charged with preventing or controlling disease, injury, or disability.   
Law enforcement: We may disclose protected health information about you for law enforcement purposes as required by law or in response to a valid subpoena or other legal process. 

**To avert a serious threat to health or safety:** We may use and disclose your protected health information when necessary to prevent a serious threat to your health and safety or the health and safety of the public or another person. 

**Victims of abuse, neglect, or domestic violence:** We may disclose your protected health information to public authorities, as allowed, to report suspected abuse, neglect, or domestic violence. 

**Health oversight activities:** We may disclose protected health information about you to an oversight agency for activities authorized by law. These oversight activities include audits, investigations and inspections, licensure and for the government to monitor the healthcare system, government programs, and compliance with civil rights laws. 

**Business associates:** There are some services provided by us through contracts with business associates. For example, we may use a collection service for overdue accounts. When we contract these services, we may disclose protected health information about you to our business associates so that they can perform the job we have asked them to do and bill you or your third-party payor for services rendered. To protect protected health information about you, we require all business associates to appropriately safeguard the protected health information. 

**Judicial and administrative proceedings:** We may disclose your protected health information in the course of any judicial or administrative proceeding, with your consent, or as directed by a court order signed by a judge or as allowed or required by law. 

**Research:** We may disclose protected health information about you to researchers when their research has been approved by an institutional review board that has reviewed the research proposal and established protocols to ensure the privacy of your information. 

Coroners, medical examiners, and funeral directors: We may release protected health information about you to a coroner or medical examiner. This may be necessary, for example, to identify a deceased person or to determine the cause of death. We may also disclose protected health information consistent with applicable law to funeral directors to carry out their duties.   
Organ or tissue procurement organizations: Consistent with applicable law, we may disclose protected health information about you to organ procurement organizations or other entities engaged in the procurement, banking, or transplantation of organs for the purpose of tissue donation and transplant.   
Notification: We may use or disclose your protected health information to notify, or assist you in notifying, a family member, personal representative, or another person responsible for your care, about your location and your general condition. 

**Correctional institution:** If you are or become an inmate of a correctional institution, we may disclose protected health information to the institution or its agents when necessary for your health or the health and safety of others. 

**Military and veterans:** If you are a member of the armed forces, we may release protected health information about you as required by military command authorities. We may also release protected health information about foreign military personnel to the appropriate military authority. In addition, we may release your protected health information to help determine eligibility for benefits by the Department of Veterans Affairs. National security, intelligence activities, and protective services for the President: We may release protected health information about you to authorized federal officials for intelligence, counterintelligence, protective services to the President, and other national security activities authorized by law. 

**Your Health Information Rights**  
You have the following rights regarding your protected health information:   
You may request a restriction on certain uses and disclosures of your protected health information. You have the right to request additional restrictions on our use or disclosure of your protected health information either at our healthcare center or by sending a written request to our Privacy Office. We are not required to agree to those restrictions. It is our policy not to grant such requests. 

You may inspect or obtain a copy of your protected health information. You have the right to inspect or obtain a copy of your protected health information that we maintain in a designated record set. The designated record set may include prescription, treatment, and billing records. You may make the request either at our healthcare center or by sending a written request to our Privacy Office. We may deny your request to inspect and copy in certain limited circumstances. Our policy is to personally deliver or send the requested records to the patient at the address on record for the patient. We may charge a reasonable fee for copies, postage, and supplies that are necessary to fulfill the request.   
You may request communications of protected health information by alternate methods. You have the right to request that we communicate confidential information to you by an alternate means. For example, you may request that we call you at your work telephone number when your prescription is ready. You must state how or where you would like to be contacted. We will accommodate all reasonable requests that we may require to be in writing. 

You may request an amendment to your protected health information. You have the right to request that we change the records that we maintain about you if you feel that the information is incomplete or incorrect. You may make the request either at our healthcare center or by sending a written request to our Privacy Office. In certain circumstances, we may deny your request for amendment. All denials will be made in writing. If we deny your request, you have the right to file a statement of disagreement with the decision and we may give a rebuttal to your statement. 

You may request and receive an accounting of disclosures of your protected health information. You have the right to receive an accounting of the disclosures we have made of your protected health information after April 14, 2003 for most purposes other than treatment, payment, and operations. Such accounting of disclosures for pharmacy patients also excludes disclosures made to you, your family or friends involved in your care, or other disclosures that you authorize. The right to receive an accounting is subject to certain other exceptions, restrictions, and limitations. To request an accounting, make the request at our healthcare center or send a written request to our Privacy Office.   
You may obtain a copy of this Notice. You may ask for a paper copy of this Notice at any time, and one will be provided for you. Copies may be obtained from any of our healthcare centers. 

**Our Legal Duties**  
We will obtain your written authorization before using or disclosing your protected health information for purposes other than those listed in this Notice or as otherwise permitted or required by law. You may revoke an authorization in writing at any time. Upon receipt of the written revocation, we will stop using or disclosing protected health information about you, except to the extent that we have already taken action in reliance on the authorization or required by law.   
For More Information or to Report a Problem: If you have questions or would like additional information about our privacy practices, you may contact our Privacy Office. If you believe your privacy rights have been violated, you can file a complaint with our Privacy Office and/or with the Secretary of Health and Human Services. We will not retaliate for filing a complaint.   
Contact the Privacy Office:  
By phone: 1-866-369-HIPA (4472)

In writing:  
Privacy Office  
Shopko   
PO Box 19060  
Green Bay, WI 54307-9060  

Download our Privacy Authorization & Disclosure document.

Effective Date:  
This Notice is effective as of April 14, 2003. FORM HIPAA 0001-ENG 4/03
